DONELL TORRES

St. Louis, MO

Phone: (813) 454-3829 | Email: donelltorres@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: <u>Donell Torres</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/donellt</u> Portfolio: https://donellt.github.io/

SUMMARY

Frontend developer with over three years of experience in utilizing a creative background to create an engaging and innovative online user experience. Earned a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Central Florida, with enhanced skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, MondoDB, Node.js, React.js and progressive web applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, Diango, CSS3, LESS, SCSS, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, WordPress

Tools: Express.js, React, Node.js, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Alexandria Harmonizers | theharmonizers.org

A mobile-responsive promotional website created for a world-renowned barbershop chorus in Virginia.

• Tools/Languages used: CSS3, HTML5, WordPress, Cornerstone

E-Portfolio | Github Repo - Deployed Project

A simple mobile-responsive, E-Portfolio page created purely with best practices for CSS3 and HTML5.

Tools/Languages used: CSS3, HTML5, Git

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer Apartments247

2021 – Current Remote

Independent contractor tasked with developing sites utilizing a proprietary CMS, as well as the following languages: SCSS, LESS, CSS3, HTML5, Django, and JavaScript. *Responsibilities:*

- Complete daily tasks assigned in Asana ranging from internal requests to site redesigns.
- Daily scrum to discuss current and future projects as well as trouble areas.
- Develop the front end of sites using mockups designed in Figma by the design team.

Web Developer AudSEO

2021 – 2021

Remote

Designed and developed SEO optimized, mobile-responsive web applications for audiology professionals and hearing care centers utilizing Wordpress, CSS3, and HTML5.

Web Developer/Technical Support 2019 – 2021 **Goldman Association Management** Lutz, FL

Developed and maintained multiple mobile-responsive and user-friendly websites for several non-profit dental associations utilizing WordPress, CSS3, and HTML5.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Webmaster, <u>Alexandria Harmonizers</u> Webmaster, <u>Sunshine District of BHS</u> 2021 – Current 2020 – 2021

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development, Certificate: *University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL* A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React..

High School Diploma: *Gaither High School, Tampa, FL* Graduated from Gaither High School with a 4.7 GPA.